AFL-CIO Education Department Training Conferences and Institutes Files 5284
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
AFL-CIO Education Department Training Conferences and Institutes Files
1958- 1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO)
5284
6 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Records.
Files pertaining to training conferences and institutes.
5621173
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
MValadez, November 01, 2007
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 23, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
Working class -- Education -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Collective bargaining -- United States; AFL-CIO. Dept. of Education
5621173
- Testimony Before the Senate Labor and Public Welfare Committee, on School Construction, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  February 21, 1955
- Background for Labor on School Segregation (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letter from Florence Thorne to John Connors, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  April 20, 1950
- Publications- Workers' Education Bureau, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pocket History: Story of the American Federation of Labor, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  January 27, 1953
- Great Moments in Labor History by E.T. Kehrer, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  March, 1950
- John Burke Correspondence with Bess Roberts, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Pocket History: Labor's Story, Draft 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Southern Summer School International Chemical Workers Union, AFL-CIO, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  May 18-23, 1958
- 1961 Basic AFL-CIO Southern Labor School (Box 1, Folder 10)
  August 20-25, 1961
- Labor Summer School, Maryland State and DC, AFL-CIO, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  June 21-26, 1959
- Chemical Workers Annual Summer School, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Union Leadership Training School, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  August 17-22, 1958
- North Carolina, South Carolina and Virginia Tri-State Labor School, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  August 10-15, 1958
- Labor Education Institute, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  June14-19, 1959
- Labor Summer School, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- United Rubber Workers Manual, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  September 22-28, 1957. Lake Junaluska, North Carolina
- United Rubber Workers Region 1 School, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  July 14-19, 1957
- Education Conference, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  May 5-7, 1961
- Helping to Write Your Nation's Laws, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  February 25-March 1, 1962. March 18-22, 1962. April 8-12, 1962.
- Tri-State Labor School, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  July 15-20, 1962
- Helping to Write Your Nation's Laws, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  March-April, 1959
- 9th Annual Labor Institute, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  July 16-21, 1961
- Annual Southern School, ICWU, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  May 18-24, 1958
- Labor Summer School, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  August 21-26, 1960
- Washington-Oregon CIO Leadership Training School, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  September 25-October 1, 1955
- Labor Institute, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  June 7-12, 1959
- Indiana-Ohio CIO Education Conference, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  April 9-11, 1948
- Labor Education Conference, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  May 24-29, 1959.
- RWDSU Weekend Education Institute, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  March 4-5, 1961
- 9th Annual Labor Institute, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Labor Education Institute, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  July 12-August 29, 1959
- North Carolina, South Carolina and Virginia Tri-State Labor School, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Labor Summer School, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Oklahoma, Arkansas and Texas CIO Leadership Training School, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  November 28-December 4, 1954
- Oklahoma, Arkansas and Texas CIO Leadership Training School, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  October 23-29, 1955
- CIO Oregon-Washington Summer School, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  August 9-15, 1953
- CIO Education Conference, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  May 14,15,16, 1954
- CIO Indiana State Industrial Union Council, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Second Constitutional Education and PAC Conference. June 13-17, 1955
- Workers' Education Annual Institute, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  August 27-August 31, 1956
- Arkansas CIO Education Conference, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  for legislative political action. Spring, 1955.
- CIO Education Conference, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  May 1,2,3, 1953
- CIO Indiana and Kentucky Leadership Training Term, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  July 24-30, 1949
- CIO Tennessee Area Summer School, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  June 21-27, 1953
- MD. - VA. - District of Columbia CIO Training School, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  July 20-26, 1952
- CIO Washington-Oregon Leadership Training School, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  August 10-16, 1952
- Southern Labor School Gulf Coast Institute, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  September 9-14, 1962
- Midwest Summer School, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  August 20-26, 1961
- Helping to Write Your Nation's Laws, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Spring, 1960
- Maryland Leadership Institute, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  June 23-28, 1963
- Machinists Leadership School, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  1962
- Maryland Leadership Institute, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  June 28-July 3, 1964
- AFL-CIO Summer School, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  June 25-30, 1961
- Leadership Training School, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  June 24-July 8, 1962
- Helping to Write Your Nation's Laws, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  February 25-April 12, 1962
- Tri-State Labor School, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Local Education Program Planning, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Workers' Education Bureau Secretary, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Workers' Education Bureau, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Workers Education Bureau: Adult Education, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- W.E.B. - Fall Conference, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- AFL Correspondence, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- A.F. of L. - 1921-46, 1921-1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Institutes and Summer Schools, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- International Labor Office, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Department of Workers' Education, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- International Ladies' Garments Workers' Union: Education Department, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Carnegie Corporation, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Carroll, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Collective Bargaining Study, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Commonwealth College, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Brookwood College, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Executive Committee, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Emergency Education Program, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- American Association for Adult Education, 1921-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- American Fund for Public Service, Inc., 1921-1940 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Collective Bargaining, 1922-1935 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Beard, Charles A., 1921-1925 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Hull House, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Johnson & Johnson, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Paul W. Fuller, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Institutes, Schools, Etc., 1931-1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Workers' Education, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Southern Leadership Training School, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  June 12-18, 1955
- Upper South CIO Leadership Training School, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  September 11-17, 1955
- Maryland-Virginia Leadership Training School, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  July 19-25, 1953
- CIO Leadership Training School, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  May 31-June 6, 1953
- Southeastern Leadership Training School, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  September 16-22, 1956
- CIO Southeastern Leadership Training School, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  May 23-29, 1954
- Upper South CIO Training School, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  June 22-28, 1952
- Instructor's Manual, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- North Carolina, South Carolina and Virginia Tri-State Labor School, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- AFL-CIO Joint Labor School, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  July 14-20, 1957
- Southern Summer School International Chemical Workers Union. AFL-CIO, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  May 19-24, 1957
- Maryland Leadership Institute, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  June 24-30, 1962
- Annual Southern School, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Leadership Training School, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  International Chemical Workers Union, AFL-CIO. June 25-September 16, 1961
- Labor Education Institute, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Leadership Training School, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  June 24-July 14, 1962
- Maryland Leadership Institute, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Helping to Write Your Nation's Laws, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Southern Union Leadership Training School, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  September 8-14, 1957
- AFL-CIO Southern Leadership School Advanced Institute, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  September 14-19, 1958
- Labor Education Conference, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  September 7-12, 1958
- AFL-CIO Union Leadership Training School, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  July 13-19, 1958
- CIO Indiana-Kentucky Summer School, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  July 23-29, 1950
- AFL-CIO Southern Labor School's Advanced Institute, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  August 11-16, 1957
- ICWU: Materials For Union Officers, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- 13th Annual Kentucky Labor School Advanced Program, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Missouri-Arkansas Leadership Training School, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  September 9-15, 1956
- Helping to Write Your Nation's Laws, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  March 31-May 9, 1957
- Milwaukee AFL-CIO Joint Education Conference, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  May 24-26, 1957
- AFL-CIO Tulsa Education Conference, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  April 6, 7, and 8, 1956
- Washington Legislative Institutes For 1957 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  February 24- March 7, 1957
- Milwaukee AFL-CIO Joint Education Conference, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- AFL-CIO Union Leadership Training School, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  July 21-27, 1957
- Labor Education Institute, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  July 19-24, 1959